Welcome back. Vectorization is basically
欢迎回来 向量化通常是
the art of getting rid of explicit for loops in your code.
消除你的代码中显式循环语句的艺术
In the deep learning era safety in deep learning in practice,
在深度学习安全领域、深度学习、练习中
you often find yourself training on relatively large data sets,
你经常发现你自己训练大的数据集
because that's when deep learning algorithms tend to shine.
因为深度学习算法更加倾向于出类拔萃
And so, it's important that your code very quickly because otherwise,
所以你的代码运行得非常快非常重要，否则
if it's running on a big data set,
如果它运行在一个大的数据集上面
your code might take a long time to run then you just find
你的代码可能花费很长时间去运行，你会发现
yourself waiting a very long time to get the result.
你将要等待非常长的时间去得到结果
So in the deep learning era,
所以在深度学习领域
I think the ability to perform vectorization has become a key skill.
我认为可以去完成向量化以及变成一个关键的技巧
Let's start with an example.
让我们用一个例子开始
So, what is Vectorization?
什么是向量化？
In logistic regression you need to compute Z equals W transpose X plus B,
在逻辑回归中，你需要去计算Z=WTX+B
where W was this column vector and X is also this vector.
W是列向量，X也是列向量
Maybe there are very large vectors if you have a lot of features.
如果你有很多的特征，那么就会有一个非常大的向量
So, W and X were both these R and n R, NX dimensional vectors.
所以W和X是R内的nx维向量
So, to compute W transpose X,
所以去计算W'X
if you had a non-vectorized implementation,
如果你有一个非向量化的实现
you would do something like Z equals zero.
你将会做一些事情，例如Z=0
And then for I in range of n-X.
*pythn代码   i in range(n-x)
So, for I equals 1, 2 NX,
*python代码  所以i=1,2....nx
Z plus equals W I times XI.
Z+=W[i]*X[i]
And then maybe you do Z plus equal B at the end.
所以你在最后z+=b
So, that's a non-vectorized implementation.
所以，这是一个非向量化的实现
Then you find that that's going to be really slow.
你会发现这是真的很慢
In contrast, a vectorized implementation would just compute W transpose X directly.
作为对比，一个向量化的实现将会非常直接计算WtX
In Python or a numpy,
在Python 或者numpy
the command you use for that is Z equals np.W,
你将要为那个实现的命令是Z=np.w X
X, so this computes W transpose X.
这是在计算WtX
And you can also just add B to that directly.
你也直接将要加上B
And you find that this is much faster.
你将会发现这个非常快
Let's actually illustrate this with a little demo.
让我们用一个小例子说明一下
So, here's my Jupiter notebook in which I'm going to write some Python code.
在我的Jupiter notebook 我将会写一些Python代码
So, first, let me import the numpy library to import.
首先，让我们导入numpy库
Send nP. And so, for example,
作为 np，例如
I can create A as an array as follows.
像下面这样我将要创建一个数组A
Let's say print A.
让我们看下打印A
Now, having written this chunk of code,
现在，写下这些代码块
if I hit shift enter,
如果我在键盘敲击shift 和 enter 两个键
then it executes the code.
它将要执行这个代码
So, it created the array A and it prints it out.
所以，它创建了数组A以及打印它
Now, let's do the Vectorization demo.
现在，让我们完成向量化的例子
I'm going to import the time libraries,
我将要导入time库
since we use that,
因为我要使用那个
in order to time how long different operations take.
为了去计算两次不同的操作花费了多长时间
Can they create an array A?
他们能创建一个数组A吗
Those random thought rand.
通过rand函数随机得到
This creates a million dimensional array with random values.
用随机值创建了一个百万维度的数组
b = np.random.rand.
Another million dimensional array.
另外一个百万维度的数组
And, now, tic=time.time, so this measure the current time,
现在 tic=time.time，记录一下当前时间
c = np.dot (a, b).
toc = time.time.
And this print,
打印一下
it is the vectorized version.
向量化的版本
It's a vectorize version.
这是一个向量化的版本
And so, let's print out.
现在让我们打印一下
Let's see the last time,
让我们看一下运行时间
so there's toc - tic x 1000,
python代码*  toc - tic x 1000
so that we can express this in milliseconds.
所以我们表达这个在毫秒级上
So, ms is milliseconds.
ms代表毫秒
I'm going to hit Shift Enter.
我将要同时敲击Shift和 Enter
So, that code took about three milliseconds or this time 1.5,
所以这个代码花费3毫秒或者这个时间的1.5倍
maybe about 1.5 or 3.5 milliseconds at a time.
或许大概 1.5 或者3.5毫秒
It varies a little bit as I run it,
它有点变化当我再次运行它的时候
but looks like maybe on average it's taking like 1.5 milliseconds,
但是好像，平均她要花费1.5毫秒
maybe two milliseconds as I run this.
或许我这次运行是2毫秒
All right.
是的
Let's keep adding to this block of code.
让我们继续增加这个代码
That's not implementing non-vectorize version.
这是非向量化的版本
Let's see, c = 0,
让我们看看，c=0
then tic = time.time.
tic = time.time.
Now, let's implement a for loop.
现在它实现了一个for 循环
For I in range of 1 million,
python 代码:for i in range 1:1000000
I'll pick out the number of zeros right.
我将要取出0右边的数字
C += (a,i) x (b,
C += (a,i) x (b,i)
i), and then toc = time.time.
以及 toc = time.time.
Finally, print more than explicit for loop.
最后，打印for loop
The time it takes is this 1000 x toc - tic + "ms"
它花费的时间是1000*toc-tic ms
to know that we're doing this in milliseconds.
为了知道我们正在做这个在毫秒级别
Let's do one more thing.
让我们再做点其他的事情
Let's just print out the value of C we
我们打印出C的值。
compute it to make sure that it's the same value in both cases.
计算一下它，确认在两个案例中他们是相同的。
I'm going to hit shift enter to run this and check that out.
我打算去敲击shift和enter去运行这个，检查一下结果
In both cases, the vectorize version
在两个案例中，向量化版本
and the non-vectorize version computed the same values,
和非向量化版本计算了相同的值
as you know, 2.50 to 6.99, so on.
正如你知道的，2.50 到 6.99
The vectorize version took 1.5 milliseconds.
向量化版本花费了1.5毫秒
The explicit for loop and non-vectorize version took about 400, almost 500 milliseconds.
很明确，for loop和非向量化版本花费了大约400，几乎500毫秒
The non-vectorize version took something like 300
非向量化版本多花费了300
times longer than the vectorize version.
倍向量化版本的时间
With this example you see that if only you remember to vectorize your code,
用这个例子你将会看见如果你仅仅记住去向量化你的代码
your code actually runs over 300 times faster.
你的代码完全运行300倍快
Let's just run it again.
让我们再次运行一下它
Just run it again.
再次运行一下它
Yeah. Vectorize version 1.5 milliseconds seconds and the for loop.
向量化版本1.5毫秒，循环使用了
So 481 milliseconds, again,
481毫秒
about 300 times slower to do the explicit for loop.
大约慢300倍用循环做这个
If the time slows down,
如果时间变慢
it's the difference between your code taking maybe one minute to
这个有很大的不同在你的代码花费一分钟去运行和
run versus taking say five hours to run.
花费5个小时去运行
And when you are implementing deep learning algorithms,
当你正在实现深度学习算法
you can really get a result back faster.
你能真正的快速得到一个返回的结果
It will be much faster if you vectorize your code.
它将会更快，如果你向量化你的代码
Some of you might have heard that a lot of
你可能听过很多这样的话
scaleable deep learning implementations are done on a GPU or a graphics processing unit.
大规模的深度学习使用了GPU或者图像处理单元实现
But all the demos I did just now in the Jupiter notebook where actually on the CPU.
但是我做的所有的案例都是在Jupiter notebook上面实现，这里只有CPU
And it turns out that both GPU and CPU have parallelization instructions.
CPU和GPU都有并行化的指令
They're sometimes called SIMD instructions.
他们有时候会叫做SIMD指令
This stands for a single instruction multiple data.
这个代表了一个单独指令多维数据
But what this basically means is that,
这个的基础意义是什么？
if you use built-in functions such as this
如果你使用了built-in函数，像这样
np.function or other functions that don't require you explicitly implementing a for loop.
np.function 或者 并不要求你实现循环的函数
It enables Python numpy to take
python的numpy充分
much better advantage of parallelism to do your computations much faster.
利用并行化去更快的计算
And this is true both computations on CPUs and computations on GPUs.
这是事实在GPU和CPU上面计算
It's just that GPUs are remarkably good at
GPU更加擅长
these SIMD calculations but CPU is actually also not too bad at that.
SIMD计算但是CPU事实上也不是太差
Maybe just not as good as GPUs.
可能没有GPU那么擅长吧
You're seeing how vectorization can significantly speed up your code.
你看下，怎么向量化能够加速你的代码
The rule of thumb to remember is whenever possible,
经验法则是无论什么时候
avoid using explicit four loops.
避免使用显式的for循环
Let's go onto the next video to see some more examples of
让我们进入到下一个视频去看下更多的向量化的案例
vectorization and also start to vectorize logistic regression.
和开始去向量化逻辑回归